Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
NORTH KOREAN CIVILIAN
POLICE UNIT DEMILITARIZED ZONE
TENACIOUS EXPLORER
AMUNDSEN
SOUTH
MINES
We love the phrase "in one go"
Over the mountain in one go
Over the river in one go
HOW HARD ARE YOU WORKING TODAY
This is the final moment of deserters!
FINAL MOMENT OF DESERTERS
Compatriots of North Korea.
this is the Sound of Freedom.
This bell represents
freedom. peace and hope.
Did we come too far?
We might come across Southern soldiers.
We could just wave at them.
what's the big deal?
Birds are flying low. it might rain soon.
It'll pour in 2 days.
Rain? It's gonna rain?
Not according to the forecast.
Yes. I heard there will be
a shower in 4 days.
2 days earlier than the forecast?
Foot soldier Kim Dong-hyuk
is better than high tech...
How will we go on without you?
Can't you stay here and not discharge?
Are you so desperate
to get your ribs smashed?
I endured 10 long years.
I won't even look back
when I walk out of here.
What'll you do outside?
I got... no plans.
But I'll live to the fullest.
Will you go to college?
Nonsense!
He's from a bottom dwelling
third-rate family.
He's bound for farms or coal mines.
So bleak. his future is bleak.
Look at these bitches crawling up my ass.
If you don't wish to be
cut up like this boar.
use your damn tongues to taste this meat.
We received a report that
boars were loitering in the minefield.
Shut your trap.
As you know. over 15 men
have been evaced for malnutrition.
Why are you telling me that?
We couldn't free the boar
we found during canvasing.
Boar?
That's right. sir.
I thought it could replenish
our men's health...
That's why you crossed
the demarcation line?
How will you lead the revolution
with that mindset?!
I'll put this lunatic in front of
the executive summary.
This is Supreme Leader's manual.
Look at this.
He instructed us to eat
as much meat as possible.
That's exactly what
Sgt. Lim here is doing.
Then I'll go ahead and feed my men.
But there's an order to things.
Cheers!
Thank you.
Our Supreme Leader announced.
"Deserters do not exist in my book."
and ordered the troops to be vigilant
with monitoring each other...
3668 says. "We'll have fried chicken
for my bro's birthday tonight.
but I'm fighting with my dad
whether to order fried or seasoned.
Isn't seasoned chicken the norm?"
Enjoy both types with your family.
We'll send you a coupon.
Let's hear the next story.
"Hello. I live in Seoul
and I'm 28 years old.
People say I'm too old to
take on a new challenge.
but I will take on my dream head on.
In a world that sets my boundaries.
I thought. 'No point in struggling.'
'Why is my life so messed up?'
I always blamed myself.
Then I came to a realization.
If I don't take action.
nothing will get accomplished.
I have to seek my own happiness.
That's why I want to
take up this challenge.
Please cheer me on as I start again.
Thank you. Mint Choco."
Here's your song request.
Zion T's Yanghwa Bridge.
I was always alone at home
LIM KYU-NAM
My dad was a taxi driver
DREAM?
When asked. he'd say
He's at "Yanghwa Bridge"
Every morning. he'd leave me
Candy and ramen snack
SOCCER PLAYER
RICH
I'd wait for his gift
In his pocket after his shift
I remember the young me
Mom. dad. and me
TENACIOUS EXPLORER
AMUNDSEN
EXPLORER
I was the baby of the family
I remember those days
I remember
Let's be happy
Don't be sick
MY DEAR SON
LIVE A HAPPY LIFE - MOM
I'm making money
I'm making all the money
I used to ask my mom
For 10 cents
My mom and dad
Even my dog rely on me now
I heard you volunteered for
tomorrow night's DMZ search party.
Will you defect to the South?
Are you out of your goddamn mind?
Aren't you moving up the schedule
because of the early rain?
The rain could move the mine locations.
Let's be happy!
I saw it all!
I saw you with my eyes!
You saw a ghost. that's what you saw.
The demilitarized zone is
full of roaming ghosts.
If you go waggle your tongue.
I will cut off your head.
Got it?
Kyu-nam. please take me with you.
Tomorrow is my mom's birthday.
I miss her terribly.
I need to know how she's doing
with my little sister in the South...
SOLDIER'S NOTEBOOK
Comrade Kim Dong-hyuk.
I'll forget about today.
You did not see anything.
and I didn't hear anything.
Dong-hyuk.
You wanted this. right?
I don't need it since I'm discharging.
Take it.
Thank you.
- Rise!
- Deserter on the loose!
We got a deserter! Come on out!
Hurry up!
Move to the barbed-wire fence!
- To the barbed-wire fence!
- This way! Go!
Get moving!
Go!
Run! Hurry up!
Kim Dong-hyuk!
Where is the hole? Where did you dig it?
Let's head back.
I'll get shot if I do!
No. I diverted the platoon.
let's head back.
You were going to go anyway.
I'm gonna go alone.
I just need to dig this!
Dong-hyuk!
Lead the way!
Lower the gun. this is not the time to go.
Rain will start before dawn.
we'll lose our window!
I know. so let's defect
while canvasing the DMZ. okay?
I don't know this route.
so we're as good as dead.
Let's use my route later tonight.
Where's the map?
Platoon leader. it's no big deal.
Comrade Kim has an illness. he sleepwalks.
He unknowingly got out...
Deserter. does this hurt?
It's not over.
You made this.
Am I right?
Dong-hyuk. then is this yours?
If you keep your mouth shut.
you'll take the fall.
Don't you know what that means?
Firing squad.
What happened was...
It's mine!
Comrade Lim didn't do anything wrong!
You're so full of shit.
State Security is en route!
You mean Field Officer Li Hyun-sang?
EVIDENCE #4
SOUTH
SOLDIER'S NOTEBOOK
EXECUTIVE SUMMARY
AND PUNISHMENT COMMITTEE
We'll now begin the executive summary!
Lim Kyu-nam and Kim Dong-hyuk
committed a serious offense
of deserting in tandem.
Judging by this map. they've been
planning for a long time.
and both must be executed
to uphold discipline in the Party!
Yes. of course.
I'm sorry. please don't kill me...
But...
according to this report.
Kim confessed to making the map.
Then why is Sgt. Lim getting punished?
They were very close for a long time...
Very close?
Very close...
- Lt. Park Joon-pyong.
- Yes. sir!
Tell me.
Is there any evidence that
Sgt. Lim made the map?
Very triumphant.
A desertion was attempted by your men.
and yet you all look triumphant.
I'll explain this one more time.
When Kim attempted desertion.
Sgt. Lim tried to apprehend him.
even though he cared about him.
Did you not say Lim was in control
of Kim when they were caught?
- That's right. sir!
- Is that true?
- That's the truth.
What's more important than
facts during a judgment?
To analyze this incident with truth...
REWARD AND PUNISHMENT COMMITTEE
Supreme Leader is unhappy with
deserters popping up in our republic.
And do you think it's a good idea
to report about 2 deserters?
Or say that we have a hero
within our ranks.
who caught the deserter?
Hey. Kyu-nam.
It's been a while.
Kyu-nam. were you trying to desert?
Not at all.
I was only trying to catch the deserter.
Right? You don't have
the conviction to desert.
Like father. like son.
Come on. focus on the road.
When your father drove for us.
he was always so calm.
Remember my dog. Thunder?
He loved sleeping when he drove.
Is your mother well?
She must be happy about your discharge.
She passed away last year.
Oh my...
I think I heard that news.
No one to return home to.
it must trouble you quite a bit.
What will you do afterwards?
I have no troubles.
I will perform my duties
to wherever the Party assigns me to.
Bastard. that's why I like you.
You know how to accept your fate.
Comrade Field Officer!
I'm older and I outrank you.
but call me "bro" like before.
Bro. where are we going?
You should tell me where...
Director General is having a banquet
at the division HQ today.
and Division Commander.
or my father-in-law.
needs something to boast about.
so you'll have to be in top form.
What do I do...
Kyu-nam.
You're a hero who caught a deserter. no?
Right.
HYUNPOONG-RI
Here is today's forecast.
Pyongyang enjoyed seasonal
weather of 11 degrees today.
It's cloudy throughout. and the forecast
has changed to heavy showers around 7 p.m.
FOR FREEDOM
AND HAPPINESS OF PEOPLE
This is my son-in-law!
You must be comrade Li Taek-gi's son.
My father told me so much about you. sir.
Did you not come with your wife?
She's pregnant. so. she's at home.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
It's been a while.
but you came so far for us.
Thank you!
My dearest comrades of Division 1.
and our distinguished guests.
Please accept my deepest appreciation
for your valiant trust
for our Supreme Leader.
and our great Party.
and for the advancement of the republic
and happiness of our people.
we must push forward
so that we do not lag behind...
We must call upon a hero.
who fulfilled his task
to the best of his abilities!
Sgt. Lim Kyu-nam!
What was it like to catch
a reactionary deserter?
This was only possible
due to the foresightedness
of the guidance by Division Commander.
I'd like to dedicate this honor to him!
Why are you walking around
like a mutt holding piss?
It's getting late.
I must return to my base...
You don't have to.
Pardon?
You're now assigned to the division HQ.
Aide to the commander.
I'm looking out for you.
so let's get you set up.
Come on. let's move!
Field Officer!
Are you courteous or just trolling?
I told you to call me "bro"!
I'm about to discharge.
why am I reassigned here?
Stay in the military.
you got nothing better outside.
Being an aide is nothing special.
Do some chores and drive him around.
But how could you decide
my future on your own?
Then do you decide your future?
Kyu-nam.
Not everyone gets a chance
like this. don't you know?
Look over there. he's here for you.
Go on.
Well noted.
But let me go back to my base first.
This is all too sudden.
I need to say goodbye
to my men and retrieve my things.
What did you leave behind?
Wasn't this your father's?
Keep it safe.
Don't be distracted and accept it.
This is your fate.
Comrade Lim Kyu-nam.
let's go.
Can I get a photo of me?
TRANSFER FORM
ONE MUST RELY ON HIMSELF
MILITARY DEMARCATION LINE PASS
You must be so busy with work
but you're so family-oriented.
Charity and loyalty to country
begin at home.
Did you stop playing piano?
Haven't heard the rumor?
I heard his piano skills are top-notch.
I knew your fingers looked special.
Please play for us. I'd love to hear it.
I forgot everything.
Please show us.
I really did forget everything.
But even so...
- Everything okay?
- Pardon?
I came for an inspection.
No activities at the guard post. sir!
Shouldn't you be on full alert?
Give me your binoculars.
Water. water!
HYUNPOONG-RI
Good day. may I borrow some gasoline?
Got a pass?
Sgt. Lim Kyu-nam.
aide to Division 1 commander.
How does his aide
go anywhere without filling up?
Driving a vehicle alone. no less.
Get me the division commander office.
I'm on a classified mission.
Does the commander have an aide named...
SGT. LIM KYU-NAM
...Sgt. Lim Kyu-nam?
Carrying out a classified mission
on the day of transfer?
I got dispatched there for this mission.
Dispatched? Oh dear.
Are you with the State Security
or something?
You said you needed gasoline.
Come with us.
I cannot delay my mission any further.
We don't have any spare gas anyway.
Come with us over that hill
to the Hyunpoong-ri station.
Isn't the deserter from
earlier today locked up there?
His name is Kim Dong-hyuk.
How did you know that?
I told you I received an order.
Are you really from the State Security?
I cannot go into details.
but there's intel about
his co-conspirator.
and to track him down.
I need all evidence.
and his map.
HYUNPOONG-RI DMZ POLICE
This is Kim Dong-hyuk's evidence.
TRANSFER FORM
LIM KYU-NAM
I can't die... I can't die...
Hey. Kim Dong-hyuk.
Forgive me...
I'm sorry...
Why are you sorry for missing your mother?
I told you we'll leave together tonight.
Let's go.
All done? No trouble
carrying out your mission?
All seems to be in order here
at Hyunpoong-ri under your supervision.
I'll make sure to include it in my report.
- No need.
- Sir.
Are you my girlfriend?
How dare you whisper in front of him!
Comrade Lim requested gasoline.
but this vehicle requires diesel!
It's suspicious that he doesn't know
what his operation vehicle takes!
Are you suspecting
our State Security comrade?
He was dispatched today.
that could happen.
Please do not take any offense.
Not at all.
I learned something about your alertness.
Very good. complete alertness.
We always strive for it.
but it never reaches a desired level.
and we'll cooperate with you
to the best of my abilities.
since you took kindly to us.
Thank you.
Hey!
Get him going with a vehicle
and one of our men.
Just the vehicle would be fine.
My mission could be delayed
if I move in a group...
Not at all.
There may be backlash
if we don't support you fully.
Just as precaution. I'll back you up.
He's Sgt. Lim Kyu-nam.
Who is it?
A State Security agent I know.
I asked him about you.
he doesn't know you.
My affiliation and mission are classified.
don't you know?
It'd be great if you could verify
who your direct superior is.
Why? Can't remember your superior's name?
Put me through to Li Hyun-sang.
Is he still at the banquet?
He sent me on a mission
while he has fun at the banquet.
By the way. why are you
in bed with the DMZ Police?
Watch your mouth before
I shove your head up your ass!
Comrade Li. there may be a problem.
Lt. Hong Su...
Shut your mouth and answer my questions.
Yes. our current location...
Comrade Li. the mission is going well.
Kyu-nam. what will you do?
What's wrong with doing what I want to do?
Come back. I'll make sure
your punishment is minimal.
No. I've decided my own future.
TAKE HIM BACK TO THE DIVISION
Take a right.
Isn't it left?
Right.
Step on it!
FOR THE FREEDOM
AND HAPPINESS OF PEOPLE
So loud...
That son of a bitch...
Dong-hyuk! Run!
Tell me.
How much of Lim's desertion
have you reported?
It was too crazy to report in...
My apologies. sir!
No need to apologize. you did good.
Commander. it hasn't been reported...
Hey. you! Hey! Hey!
Are you out of your damn mind?
If you send me a company.
I'll wrap this up cleanly.
Yes. I'll make sure to
never inconvenience you again.
I'm gonna fuck him up...
You okay?
Which unit sent you?
Nomads. right? We're being chased too.
We're in the same boat.
Get rid of them.
Please don't kill us!
I barely got out of the holding cell
in Hyunpoong-ri!
Please don't kill us!
Sang-gu. Sang-gu...
Did you see Sang-gu?
What?
Did you see Sang-gu in the holding cell?
Say you know. say you know...
Don't try to bullshit us.
did you see him or not?
I never heard of that name.
He's so clueless...
The bushy hair?
The bushy hair next door...
"I can't die... I can't die..."
There was a boy who mumbled
while staring at the wall...
Did he say how he was caught?
I don't know. but he said
he missed his sister terribly.
Sang-gu's alive.
That's a relief.
How did you end up on the run?
We're not on the run.
We're seeking a way to live
after getting kicked out of our village.
But I'm more worried about Sang-gu.
Why don't you rescue him?
We can rescue him.
This is the Hyunpoong-ri station.
and the basement is the holding cell.
Security near the entrance is too tight.
so the only way in is...
a window around back.
It must be locked.
No. guards open it
during cigarette breaks.
I saw it. I saw it with my eyes.
This guy is an expert at peeping.
it must be true.
We rescue him tomorrow.
Miss...
don't lose hope.
There's nothing here.
You make the judgment?
Push forward.
It's the pursuit unit.
Stop.
What's above you?
Desertion route found.
there's a hole in the ceiling.
The pursuit unit. take the right.
Split into left and right flanks.
Rear unit. deploy.
Cease fire.
Cease fire!
Search the valley.
Kyu-nam.
No one will get out of here alive.
Deserters spotted. 3 o'clock!
Are you deaf?!
2 deserters couldn't fire
all those bullets!
Get back to your position. get back!
THE BASTARD I LOVED
What do you want?
I enjoyed your performance.
Not as good as you used to be.
What happened to the winner
of international piano competitions?
I'm hanging up.
I'm working.
What work?
Chasing a mutt who fled home.
You can't forget it. can you?
Our days in Russia...
At the Saint Petersburg theatre...
Tired?
Not at all...
We're almost there. right?
You said that over a dozen times.
Fine. but why must we
head back to our base?
If we take an unknown path.
mines will blow us up.
and reaching the mess hall
is as good as being in the South.
that's what you said a dozen times.
Fine. fine. but...
Please stop asking me.
Talking is harder than walking.
- Dong-hyuk...
- Yes?
What do you want to eat
when you reach the South?
Meat...
There are many kinds of meat.
do you want beef or pork?
Chicken...
Many types of chicken too.
Chicken? Half fried?
Seasoned half.
Chug it down with ice cold beer.
damn. that must be heaven.
Ryu. I don't think you're
fit to be a soldier.
No. sir!
What was your dream before?
Go and fulfill that dream.
My apologies. sir!
Prove to me that your decision
is not wrong.
WARNING - THIS IS A MILITARY
BASE. TRESPASSERS WILL BE SHOT
MESS HALL
If rain moves those mines.
my map is useless.
- We have to hurry.
- Okay.
Proud men of DMZ Police!
I am State Security
Field Officer Li Hyun-sang!
Due to my negligence.
two deserters are on the loose!
However!
They will never set
foot outside this base.
and their lives will be cut short!
For this to happen.
I need your full support.
and whoever brings back their bodies.
will be given the title
of a hero!
MESS HALL
Lim Kyu-nam!
I'm gonna be a hero for once!
Open up. you traitor!
Smash it down!
Hurry up! Smash it!
I'll kill that backstabbing traitor!
Deserter on the loose!
Heading for the forward post!
Towards the ridge!
We are almost there.
they can't follow us now!
Dong-hyuk. what are you doing?!
Dong-hyuk!
Kyu-nam. give this necklace to her.
It's my mom's... birthday present...
If I can't give this to her.
I'd be too ashamed...
Let's go! We can do this!
Thank you...
SOUTH
The DMZ gates are open.
...but we wanted... take off.
so we decided... go on a trip.
Eat plenty. take tons of photos.
experience everything. and have...
MINES
I will die on my own terms...
and live on my own terms.
We should go around. sir.
MILITARY DEMARCATION LINE
I thought I'd never see you again.
Do you know what I just stepped on?
Give me your gun. then I'll let you go.
That'd be wrong.
Give it to me at once.
You can head back and I'll be on my way.
You'll head back that way.
No. it's this way.
Kyu-nam. you think
the South will be paradise?
Do you think they'll let you be free.
not caring where you're from?
No such paradise exists.
At least I can fail.
Doing things that
I want to do and failing.
trying again and failing some more...
Isn't that great?
We can't even fail here.
I'm going there to fail
as much as I desire.
You think there was nothing
I wanted to do?
It's about just living.
Struggling is futile.
I'll find out if that's true
if I challenge myself.
Aren't you glad that I tried?
Piano bro...
Do whatever you want to do.
What do you know. asshole!
What the hell do you know?
Not a damn thing!
Die! Just die!
Don't follow me.
Compatriots of North Korea.
this is the Sound of Freedom.
This bell represents
freedom. peace and hope.
South Korea promises you
happiness and freedom.
If you have hope.
don't be afraid to knock.
TELEPHONE FOR DEFECTORS
North Korean People's Army.
Sgt. Lim Kyu-nam. I wish to defect!
SOUTH KOREA WELCOMES YOU
I wish to defect!
SOUTHERN LIMIT LINE
Go.
and fail as much as you want.
If you move. you'll be shot!
You are violating
a UN peacekeeping treaty!
If you fire. we will respond forcefully!
Did you request defection?
I wish to defect...
TENACIOUS EXPLORER
AMUNDSEN
TO KYU-NAM
FEAR A MEANINGLESS LIFE.
NOT DEATH ITSELF.
- HAPPY BIRTHDAY
- PIANO BRO
Bastard...
MAKE THE WORLD REVERE US
1 YEAR LATER
HELLO. I AM...
YOUTH TRAVEL INITIATIVE
SUMMER TRAVEL PACKAGE PROPOSAL
Hello. Dong-hyuk's mother.
Whenever Dong-hyuk went into the DMZ.
he'd not only catch rabbits.
but even a boar one time.
and fed the entire base.
Everyone greased their tummies
for once. and we all had diarrhea...
And he was so accurate
with predicting weather.
Whenever Dong-hyuk wanted to do laundry...
My boy should be doing well. right?
Of course. he should be
living a happy life.
We got a handwritten letter for once.
I lived a long time
by sacrificing so much.
I wasted away days on end
without a shred of ambition.
But I had this thought
of wanting something.
even if it's very small.
that I can accomplish on my own.
I guess I wanted to see me in that state.
That was my dream.
So did I achieve my dream? Am I happy?
I honestly don't know.
Life is still difficult.
and I sometimes cry for no reason.
YOUR YOUTH BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT
PROPOSAL HAS BEEN APPROVED.
But I work up my strength at that moment.
I can't just stay put.
That's why I'm happy right now.
Thank you. Amundsen.
Here's the song you requested.
Be happy.
Subtitle translation by: Tae Jo
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm